traclist.com 2017-02-08

# 

**Privacy Policy of traclist.com**

In order to receive information about your Personal Data, the purposes and the parties the Data is shared with, contact the Owner.

 **Data Controller and Owner**

Traclist.com C/O CC Hub, 1st Floor, 294 Herbert Macaulay Rd, Lagos,[info@traclist.com](mailto:info@traclist.com)

 **Introduction**

Hello, welcome to Traclist. As you use our services, we want you to be clear how we’re using information and the ways in which you can protect your privacy. 

Our Privacy Policy explains: 

What information we collect and why we collect it. 

How we use that information. 

The choices we offer, including how to access and update information.

And other related information

Click on the links below to jump to each section of these terms:

Personally identifiable information

Device Information

Advertising Partners

Types of Data collected

Cookies

Mode and Place of Processing the Data

Changing or Deleting Your Information

Security

Additional information about Data collection and processing

Rights of Users

Changes to this Privacy Policy

Link to other sites

Our policy towards children

How to contact us

 **Personally Identifiable Information**

When you register with us through the Site or Applications to become a Member of Traclist, we may ask you for personally identifiable information. This refers to information about you that can be used to contact or identify you ("Personal Information"). Personal Information includes, but is not limited to, your name, username, phone number, credit card and other billing information, email address, shipping address, and your friends’ email addresses (which we will only use in order to invite them to use the Service). 

We may also collect information you supply to us regarding your personal preferences and interests. You can choose not to provide us with any or all of the information we specify or request, but then you may not be able to register with us or to take advantage of some or all of our features. You can register to join Traclist via the Site or Applications or by logging into your account with certain third party social networking sites ("SNS") (including Facebook and Twitter) via our Site. If you decide to create your Account by logging into a SNS via the Site, we may extract the Personal Information you have provided to the SNS (such as your "real" name, email address and other information you make publicly available via the SNS) from the account you have with such SNS and use that information to create your Account; the information we extract may depend on the privacy settings you have with the SNS.

We use your Personal Information mainly to provide the Service and administer your inquiries. We will create your Account for your use of the Site and Applications based upon the Personal Information you provide and you will become a Member of Traclist.

We also collect the other information that you provide as part of registration and the administration and personalization of your profile webpage on Traclist (e.g., without limitation, age and individual preferences) ("Non-Identifying Information").

We use your Personal Information (in some cases, in conjunction with your Non-Identifying Information) mainly to provide the Service, complete your transactions, and administer your inquiries.

Certain Non-Identifying Information would be considered a part of your Personal Information if it were combined with other identifiers (for example, combining your zip code with your street address) in a way that enables you to be identified. But the same pieces of information are considered Non-Identifying Information when they are taken alone or combined only with other non-identifying information (for example, your viewing preferences). 

We may combine your Personal Information with Non-Identifying Information and aggregate it with information collected from other Traclist Users (defined below) to attempt to provide you with a better experience, to improve the quality and value of the Service and to analyze and understand how our Site, Applications and Service are used. We may also use the combined information without aggregating it to serve you specifically, for instance to deliver a product to you according to your preferences or restrictions.

We also use your Personal Information to contact you with Traclist newsletters, marketing or promotional materials and other information that may be of interest to you. If you decide at any time that you no longer wish to receive such communications from us, please follow the unsubscribe instructions provided in any of the communications or update your "preferences" information. (See "Changing or Deleting Information," below.)

Log Data. When you visit the Site or Applications, whether as a Member or a non-registered user just browsing (any of these, a "Traclist User"), our servers automatically record information that your browser sends whenever you visit a website ("Log Data"). This Log Data may include information such as your Internet Protocol address, the browser type or the webpage you were visiting before you came to our Site and Application, pages of our Site and Application that you visit, the time spent on those pages, information you search for on our Site and Application, access times and dates, and other statistics. 

We may use this information to monitor and analyze use of the Site, Applications and the Service and for the Site and Applications’ technical administration, to increase our Site and Applications’ functionality and user-friendliness, and to better tailor our Site and Applications to our visitors’ needs. For example, some of this information is collected so that when you visit the Site and Application again, it may recognize you and serve advertisements and other information appropriate to your interests. We also use this information to verify that visitors to the Site and Application meet the criteria required to process their requests. 

We do not treat Log Data as Personal Information or use it in association with other Personal Information, though we may aggregate, analyze and evaluate such information for the same purposes as stated above regarding other Non-Identifying Information.

 **Device Information**

In addition to Log Data, we may also collect information about the device you’re using Traclist on, including what type of device it is, what operating system you’re using, device settings, unique device identifiers, and crash data. Whether we collect some or all of this information often depends on what type of device you’re using and its settings. To learn more about what information your device makes available to us, please also check the policies of your device manufacturer or software provider

In order to allow Traclist and our Advertisers to reach the best inventory online, we work with third party advertising companies (our “Advertising Partners”) and product merchants to help us recognize you and serve relevant advertisements to you when you visit a website or online service in their network. 

**Advertising Partners**

We also work with Advertising Partners who help us recognize you across different devices in order to show you relevant advertisements. Our Advertising Partners may collect information about your activities on our website, our Advertisers’ websites, and other websites or online services in their networks. We also work with third party companies to assist us with website analytics such as evaluating the use and operation of our website so that we can continue to enhance the website and our services.

 **Types of Data collected**

In addition to biometric data on our users, Traclist collects data about your activities that does not personally or directly identify you when you visit our website, the website of entities for which we serve advertisements (our “Advertisers”), or the websites and online services where we display advertisements (“Publishers”). 

This information may include the content you view, the date and time that you view this content, the products you purchase, or your location information associated with your IP address. We use the information we collect to serve you more relevant advertisements (referred to as “Retargeting”). We collect information about where you saw the ads we serve you and what ads you clicked on.

We do not target ads to you based on sensitive personal data, such as information related to race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs or other beliefs of a similar nature, trade union membership, physical or mental health or condition or sexual life. Where permitted by law, we do work with health and fitness companies and may show you more relevant ads based on your perceived interest in these topics.

Traclist may target ads based on data provided by Advertisers or partners alone or in combination with the data we collect ourselves. Any data used to serve targeted advertisements is de-identified and is not used to personally or directly identify you. We require third parties, including Publishers, to provide notice and obtain appropriate consent, where required by applicable law.

The Personal Data may be freely provided by the User, or collected automatically when using this Application.

 **Cookies**

Like many websites, our Site and Applications use "cookies" to collect information. A cookie is a small data file that we transfer to your computer or mobile device’s hard disk for record-keeping purposes. We use cookies for two purposes. First, we utilize persistent cookies to save your login information for future logins to the Site and Applications. Second, we utilize session ID cookies to enable certain features of the Site and Applications, to better understand how you interact with the Site and Applications and to monitor aggregate usage by Traclist Users and web traffic routing on the Site and Applications. 

Unlike persistent cookies, session cookies are deleted from your computer when you log off from the Site, Applications and Service and then close your browser. Third party advertisers on the Site and Applications may also place or read cookies on your browser. You can instruct your browser, by changing its options, to stop accepting cookies or to prompt you before accepting a cookie from the websites you visit. If you do not accept cookies, however, you may not be able to use all portions of the Site and Applications or all functionality of the Service.

Any use of Cookies - or of other tracking tools - by this Application or by the owners of third party services used by this Application, unless stated otherwise, serves to identify Users and remember their preferences, for the sole purpose of providing the service required by the User.

Failure to provide certain Personal Data may make it impossible for this Application to provide its services.

The User assumes responsibility for the Personal Data of third parties published or shared through this Application and declares to have the right to communicate or broadcast them, thus relieving the Data Controller of all responsibility.

 **Mode and place of processing the Data**

 **Methods of processing**

The Data Controller processes the Data of Users in a proper manner and shall take appropriate security measures to prevent unauthorized access, disclosure, modification, or unauthorized destruction of the Data.

The Data processing is carried out using computers and/or IT enabled tools, following organizational procedures and modes strictly related to the purposes indicated. In addition to the Data Controller, in some cases, the Data may be accessible to certain types of persons in charge, involved with the operation of the site (administration, sales, marketing, legal, system administration) or external parties (such as third party technical service providers, mail carriers, hosting providers, IT companies, communications agencies) appointed, if necessary, as Data Processors by the Owner. The updated list of these parties may be requested from the Data Controller at any time.

 **Place**

The Data is processed at the Data Controller's operating offices and in any other places where the parties involved with the processing are located. For further information, please contact the Data Controller.

 **Retention time**

The Data is kept for the time necessary to provide the service requested by the User, or stated by the purposes outlined in this document, and the User can always request that the Data Controller suspend or remove the data.

 **7\. Changing or Deleting Your Information**

All Members may review, update, correct or delete the Personal Information in their Account by contacting us or by editing such profile via the Site and Applications. If you completely delete all such information, then your Account may become deactivated. We will use commercially reasonable efforts to honor your request. We may retain an archived copy of your records as required by law or for legitimate business purposes.

 **Security** ****

We may make any legally required disclosures of any breach of the security, confidentiality, or integrity of your unencrypted electronically stored "personal data" (as defined in applicable state statutes on security breach notification) to you via email or conspicuous posting on this Site or via the Application in the most expedient time possible and without unreasonable delay, insofar as consistent with (i) the legitimate needs of law enforcement or (ii) any measures necessary to determine the scope of the breach and restore the reasonable integrity of the data system.

 **Additional information about Data collection and processing**

 **Legal action**

The User's Personal Data may be used for legal purposes by the Data Controller, in Court or in the stages leading to possible legal action arising from improper use of this Application or the related services.

The User is aware of the fact that the Data Controller may be required to reveal personal data upon request of public authorities. 

**Additional information about User's Personal Data**

In addition to the information contained in this privacy policy, this Application may provide the User with additional and contextual information concerning particular services or the collection and processing of Personal Data upon request. 

**System Logs and Maintenance**

For operation and maintenance purposes, this Application and any third party services may collect files that record interaction with this Application (System Logs) or use for this purpose other Personal Data (such as IP Address). 

**Information not contained in this policy**

More details concerning the collection or processing of Personal Data may be requested from the Data Controller at any time. Please see the contact information at the beginning of this document. 

**The rights of Users**

Users have the right, at any time, to know whether their Personal Data has been stored and can consult the Data Controller to learn about their contents and origin, to verify their accuracy or to ask for them to be supplemented, cancelled, updated or corrected, or for their transformation into anonymous format or to block any data held in violation of the law, as well as to oppose their treatment for any and all legitimate reasons. Requests should be sent to the Data Controller at the contact information set out above. 

This Application does not support “Do Not Track” requests.  
To determine whether any of the third party services it uses honor the “Do Not Track” requests, please read their privacy policies. 

**Changes to this privacy policy**

The Data Controller reserves the right to make changes to this privacy policy at any time by giving notice to its Users on this page. It is strongly recommended to check this page often, referring to the date of the last modification listed at the bottom. If a User objects to any of the changes to the Policy, the User must cease using this Application and can request that the Data Controller erase the Personal Data. Unless stated otherwise, the then-current privacy policy applies to all Personal Data the Data Controller has about Users. 

**Links to Other Sites**

Our Site and Applications may contain links to other websites. If you choose to visit an advertiser by "clicking on" a banner ad or other type of advertisement, or click on another third party link, you will be directed to that third party’s website. The fact that we link to a website or present a banner ad or other type of advertisement is not an endorsement, authorization or representation of our affiliation with that third party, nor is it an endorsement of their privacy or information security policies or practices. We do not exercise control over third party websites. These other websites may place their own cookies or other files on your computer, collect data or solicit personal information from you. Other sites follow different rules regarding the use or disclosure of the personal information you submit to them. We encourage you to read the privacy policies or statements of the other websites you visit.

 **Our Policy Toward Children**

This Site and Applications are not directed to children under 13. We do not knowingly collect personally identifiable information from children under 13. If a parent or guardian becomes aware that his or her child has provided us with Personal Information without their consent, he or she should contact us at 

[info@Traclist.com](mailto:info@Traclist.com). If we become aware that a child under 13 has provided us with Personal Information, we will delete such information from our files.

 **How to contact us**

If you have any questions about this Policy or any of the practices described herein, please contact us at C/O CC Hub, 1st Floor, 294 Herbert Macaulay Rd, Lagos,[info@traclist.com](mailto:info@traclist.com)
